MICHAEL GAUTHIER

Victoria, BC • 236-969-6116 • migauth@outlook.com

• www.github.com/migauth • www.linkedin.com/in/migauth

Professional Summary

Full stack web developer blending expertise in inclusive education and creative practices. Emphasizes the creation of effective, adaptable, and test-focused code. Values community engagement and effective communication. Demonstrates outstanding leadership and organizational capabilities.

Skills

JavaScript, HTML, CSS	SQL fundamentals	Python
-----------------------	------------------	--------

React proficiency Ruby on Rails NodeJS

API Integration Git, Github Jest, Cypress

Projects

Michael Gauthier Portfolio, 03/2024

• Personal portfolio website. Tech Stack: Vanilla Javascript, HTML, CSS

Furniture Seller, 02/2024

• A full stack furniture selling app. Tech Stack: Javascript, EJS, SCSS

Education

Diploma, Full Stack Web Development: 05/2024

Lighthouse Labs - Victoria, BC

Certification, UEB Braille Transcription: 05/2024

PRCVI - Victoria, BC

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Art Education: 06/2014

Concordia University - Montreal, Quebec

Employment

Braille specialist and educational assistant, 03/2020 to Current

Greater Victoria School District 61

• Providing inclusive education and curriculum adaptations for blind students.

Out of school care provider, 09/2019 to 03/2020

Fairfield Gonzales Community Association

- Provided care for children grades 1-4. Groups of 15-20 students.
- Provided focused care for child with autism.

Bindery department assistant/Front desk clerk, 04/2018 to 08/2019

Island Blue Print - Victoria, BC

- Technical use of computers, printers, scanners, and various cutting and binding machines.
- Extensive use of Microsoft Word, Excel, Acrobat Pro, and Photoshop.
- Retail and general customer service.

Other Experience

Medium Case Scenarios, 03/2023 to Current

• Performer in comedy improv group of 10 participating in live performances in venues and various events.

Surprise Left, 01/2022 to Current

 Bassist in 4-piece band covering songs across multiple genres. Monthly live professional performances.